{% raw %}

Resource | Change | Status | Reason | Description
US Core Authentication Time Extension (StructureDefinition) | | retired |

THe US Core Authentication Time Extension extension has been superseded by the standard Cross-version Extension for R5.DocumentReference.attester for use in FHIR R4 and is deprecated. It SHOULD NOT be used for new or revised content. It is retained for historical/backward compatibility purposes. Implementers SHOULD use the FHIR R5 DocumentReference.attester extension instead

|

This extension indicates when the information in the document was verified.

US Core CarePlan Category Extension Codes (CodeSystem) | | retired |

This code system is no longer required and is deprecated. The concept "assess-plan" can be replicated as a local code.

|

Set of codes that are needed for implementation of the US-Core CarePlan Profile. These codes are used as extensions to the FHIR ValueSet.

US Core Gender Identity Extension (StructureDefinition) | | retired |

This extension is no longer a USCDI requirement and is deprecated. It SHOULD NOT be used for new or revised content. It is retained for historical/backward compatibility purposes. Implementers can use the HL7 standard extension instead

|

This extension represents an individual's sense of being a man, woman, boy, girl, nonbinary, or something else, ascertained by asking them what that identity is.

US Core Sex Extension (StructureDefinition) | | retired |

This extension is no longer a USCDI requirement and is deprecated. It SHOULD NOT be used for new or revised content. It is retained for historical/backward compatibility purposes. Implementers SHOULD use the US Core Individual Sex Extension instead

|

The Sex Extension is used to reflect the documentation of a person's sex. Systems choosing to record sources of information should use the Provenance resource .

USCDI includes a data element for sex, intended to support the exchange of a sex value that is not characterized as sex assigned at birth or birth sex. This Sex extension supports USCDI. Sex assigned at birth or birth sex can be recorded using the more specific US Core Birth Sex Extension . Future versions of this extension may be informed by the content of the HL7 Cross Paradigm IG: Gender Harmony - Sex and Gender Representation, which may include additional guidance on its relationship to administrative gender ( Patient.gender ).

{% endraw %}

{% raw %} US Core Authentication Time Extension 2

This extension indicates when the information in the document was verified.

US Core Birth Sex Extension 5

A code classifying the person's sex assigned at birth. This extension aligns with LOINC 76689-9 (Sex assigned at birth).

US Core Direct email Extension 3

This email address is associated with a "Direct Secure Messaging" service. This extension can only be used on contact points where the system = 'email'

US Core Ethnicity Extension 5

Concepts classifying the person into a named category of humans sharing common history, traits, geographical origin or nationality. The ethnicity codes used to represent these concepts are based upon the Race & Ethnicity - CDC (CDCREC) code system. Detailed ethnicity concepts are grouped by and pre-mapped to the 2 OMB ethnicity categories:

Hispanic or Latino
Not Hispanic or Latino.

US Core Extension Questionnaire URI 3

The location where a non-FHIR questionnaire/survey form can be found. This extension is used when the survey, form, or questionnaire which is being answered is not a FHIR Questionnaire, otherwise the canonical url for the FHIR Questionnaire is used.

US Core FamilyMemberHistory Recorder Extension 2

Individual who recorded the family member's health history and takes responsibility for its content. Because the recorder takes responsibility for accurately recording information in the record, the recorder is the most recent author. The recorder might or might not be the asserter.

US Core Gender Identity Extension 3

This extension represents an individual's sense of being a man, woman, boy, girl, nonbinary, or something else, ascertained by asking them what that identity is.

US Core Individual Sex Extension 5

USCDI includes a data element for Sex, intended to support the exchange of a recorded sex value. This extension aligns with the USCDI definition of Sex: "Documentation of a specific instance of sex." It enables systems to share the sex value as it was documented in a particular context. Systems choosing to record sources of information should use the Provenance resource.

US Core Interpreter Needed Extension 2

This extension indicates the individual's need for an interpreter to communicate healthcare information in a language other than the default language of the organization. It has the same meaning as the LOINC 54588-9 (Interpreter needed)

US Core Jurisdiction Extension 2

An extension to communicate the US state or local jurisdiction for individual and entity identifiers. For example, a practitioner's state or local jurisdiction for a license.

US Core Medication Adherence Extension 2

The Medication Adherence Extension is used to report whether a medication has been consumed according to instructions as reported by a patient or on behalf of the patient.

US Core Race Extension 5

Concepts classifying the person into a named category of humans sharing common history, traits, geographical origin or nationality. The race codes used to represent these concepts are based upon the Race & Ethnicity - CDC (CDCREC) code system. Detailed race concepts are grouped by and pre-mapped to the 5 OMB race categories:

American Indian or Alaska Native
Asian
Black or African American
Native Hawaiian or Other Pacific Islander
White.

US Core Sex Extension 2

The Sex Extension is used to reflect the documentation of a person's sex. Systems choosing to record sources of information should use the Provenance resource.

USCDI includes a data element for sex, intended to support the exchange of a sex value that is not characterized as sex assigned at birth or birth sex. This Sex extension supports USCDI. Sex assigned at birth or birth sex can be recorded using the more specific US Core Birth Sex Extension. Future versions of this extension may be informed by the content of the HL7 Cross Paradigm IG: Gender Harmony - Sex and Gender Representation, which may include additional guidance on its relationship to administrative gender (Patient.gender).

US Core Tribal Affiliation Extension 3

This Extension profile represents a tribe or band with which a person associates and, optionally, whether they are enrolled.

US Core USCDI Requirement Extension 5

This extension is only used in the US Core Implementation Guide's Profile StructureDefinition elements. It flags elements that are Additional USCDI Requirements for certified systems. In other words, elements that are not marked as Must Support but are required for Office of the National Coordinator for Health Information Technology (ONC) Health IT certification testing. See the Conformance page for more information.

{% endraw %}

{% raw %} US Core USCDI Requirement Extension

This extension is only used in the US Core Implementation Guide's Profile StructureDefinition elements. It flags elements that are Additional USCDI Requirements for certified systems. In other words, elements that are not marked as Must Support but are required for Office of the National Coordinator for Health Information Technology (ONC) Health IT certification testing. See the Conformance page for more information.

US Core ADI DocumentReference Profile

The US Core Advance Directive Information (ADI) DocumentReference Profile inherits from the FHIR DocumentReference resource; refer to it for scope and usage definitions. It sets minimum expectations for searching and fetching patient Advance Directive Information (ADI) documents using the DocumentReference resource. Examples of advance healthcare directive documents include physician order for life sustaining treatment (POLST), do not resuscitate order (DNR), and Living Will. In addition to the document contents, it communicates the type of advance directive document, the author, the verifier, and other properties. To represent whether advance directive documents exist for a patient, see the US Core Observation ADI Documentation Profile. This profile sets minimum expectations for searching and fetching patient ADI documents using the DocumentReference resource. It specifies which core elements, extensions, vocabularies, and value sets SHALL be present and constrains how the elements are used. Providing the floor for standards development for specific use cases promotes interoperability and adoption.

US Core AllergyIntolerance Profile

The US Core AllergyIntolerance Profile inherits from the FHIR AllergyIntolerance resource; refer to it for scope and usage definitions. This profile sets minimum expectations for the AllergyIntolerance resource to record, search, and fetch allergies/adverse reactions associated with a patient. It specifies which core elements, extensions, vocabularies, and value sets SHALL be present and constrains how the elements are used. Providing the floor for standards development for specific use cases promotes interoperability and adoption.

US Core Authentication Time Extension

This extension indicates when the information in the document was verified.

US Core Average Blood Pressure Profile

The US Core Average Blood Pressure Profile inherits from the Observation resource; refer to it for scope and usage definitions. This profile sets minimum expectations for recording, searching, and fetching average diastolic and systolic blood pressure observations with standard LOINC codes and UCUM units of measure. It specifies which core elements, extensions, vocabularies, and value sets SHALL be present in the resource and constrains how the elements are used. Providing the floor for standards development for specific use cases promotes interoperability and adoption.

US Core BMI Profile

The US Core BMI Profile inherits from the US Core Vital Signs Profile. This profile sets minimum expectations for the Observation resource to record, search, and fetch Body Mass Index (BMI) observations with standard LOINC codes and UCUM units of measure. It specifies which additional core elements, extensions, vocabularies, and value sets SHALL be present in the resource and constrains how the elements are used. Providing the floor for standards development for specific use cases promotes interoperability and adoption.

US Core Birth Sex Extension

A code classifying the person's sex assigned at birth. This extension aligns with LOINC 76689-9 (Sex assigned at birth).

US Core Blood Pressure Profile

US Core Blood Pressure Profile inherits from the US Core Vital Signs Profile. This profile sets minimum expectations for the Observation resource to record, search, and fetch diastolic and systolic blood pressure observations with standard LOINC codes and UCUM units of measure. It specifies which additional core elements, extensions, vocabularies, and value sets SHALL be present in the resource and constrains how the elements are used. Providing the floor for standards development for specific use cases promotes interoperability and adoption.

US Core Body Height Profile

The US Core Body Height Profile inherits from the US Core Vital Signs Profile. This profile sets minimum expectations for the Observation resource to record, search, and fetch body height observations with a standard LOINC code and UCUM units of measure. It specifies which additional core elements, extensions, vocabularies, and value sets SHALL be present in the resource and constrains how the elements are used. Providing the floor for standards development for specific use cases promotes interoperability and adoption.

US Core Body Temperature Profile

The US Core Body Temperature Profile inherits from the US Core Vital Signs Profile. This profile sets minimum expectations for the Observation resource to record, search, and fetch body temperature observations with a standard LOINC code and UCUM units of measure. It specifies which additional core elements, extensions, vocabularies, and value sets SHALL be present in the resource and constrains how the elements are used. Providing the floor for standards development for specific use cases promotes interoperability and adoption.

US Core Body Weight Profile

The US Core Body Weight Profile inherits from the US Core Vital Signs Profile. This profile sets minimum expectations for the Observation resource to record, search, and fetch body weight observations with a standard LOINC code and UCUM units of measure. It specifies which additional core elements, extensions, vocabularies, and value sets SHALL be present in the resource and constrains how the elements are used. Providing the floor for standards development for specific use cases promotes interoperability and adoption.

US Core Care Experience Preference Profile

The US Core Care Experience Preference Profile inherits from the FHIR Observation resource; refer to it for scope and usage definitions. This profile provides guidance on how to record a care experience preference expressed by the patient regarding their care and treatment. Examples include, but are not limited to, religious preferences, dislikes and fears, preferred place for birth, preferred pharmacy, and thoughts and feelings to be shared. This profile does not represent an actual order, but it can guide caregivers and medical personnel about what is important for the person. This profile sets minimum expectations for the Observation resource to record, search, and fetch for a patient care experience preferences. It specifies which core elements, extensions, vocabularies, and value sets SHALL be present in the resource and constrains how the elements are used. Providing the floor for standards development for specific use cases promotes interoperability and adoption.

US Core CarePlan Profile

The US Core CarePlan Profile inherits from the FHIR CarePlan resource; refer to it for scope and usage definitions. This profile sets minimum expectations for the CarePlan resource to record, search, and fetch assessment and plan of treatment data associated with a patient. It specifies which core elements, extensions, vocabularies, and value sets SHALL be present and constrains how the elements are used. Providing the floor for standards development for specific use cases promotes interoperability and adoption.

US Core CareTeam Profile

The US Core CareTeam Profile inherits from the FHIR CareTeam resource; refer to it for scope and usage definitions. This profile sets minimum expectations for the CareTeam resource for identifying the Care Team members associated with a patient to promote interoperability and adoption through common implementation. It specifies which core elements, extensions, vocabularies, and value sets SHALL be present in the resource and how the elements are used. Providing the floor for standards development for specific use cases promotes interoperability and adoption.

US Core Condition Encounter Diagnosis Profile

The US Core Condition Encounter Diagnosis Profile inherits from the FHIR Condition resource; refer to it for scope and usage definitions. US Core version 5.0.0 split the US Core Condition Profile into this profile and the US Core Condition Problems and Health Concerns Profile. This profile meets the requirements of the U.S. Core Data for Interoperability (USCDI) Encounter Diagnosis Data Element. It sets minimum expectations for the Condition resource to record, search, and fetch information about an encounter diagnosis. It specifies which core elements, extensions, vocabularies, and value sets SHALL be present in the resource and constrains how the elements are used. Providing the floor for standards development for specific use cases promotes interoperability and adoption.

US Core Condition Problems and Health Concerns Profile

The US Core Condition Problems and Health Concerns Profile inherits from the FHIR Condition resource; refer to it for scope and usage definitions. US Core version 5.0.0 split the US Core Condition Profile into this profile and the US Core Condition Encounter Diagnosis Profile. This profile meets the requirements of the U.S. Core Data for Interoperability (USCDI) Problems, Health Concerns, and SDOH Problems/Health Concerns Data Elements. It sets minimum expectations for the Condition resource to record, search, and fetch information about a condition, diagnosis, or another event, situation, issue, or clinical concept documented and categorized as a problem or health concern, including information about a Social Determinants of Health related condition. It specifies which core elements, extensions, vocabularies, and value sets SHALL be present in the resource and constrains how the elements are used. Providing the floor for standards development for specific use cases promotes interoperability and adoption.

US Core Coverage Profile

The US Core Coverage Profile inherits from the FHIR Coverage resource; refer to it for scope and usage definitions. This profile meets the requirements of the US Core Data for Interoperability (USCDI) Health Insurance Information Data Class. It sets minimum expectations for the Coverage resource to record, search, and fetch data related to an individual's insurance coverage for health care. It specifies which core elements, extensions, vocabularies, and value sets SHALL be present in the resource and constrains how the elements are used. Providing the floor for standards development for specific use cases promotes interoperability and adoption.

US Core Device Profile

The US Core Device Profile inherits from the FHIR Device resource; refer to it for scope and usage definitions. It sets minimum expectations for the Device resource to record, search, and fetch medical and non-medical devices (for example, software or crutches). This profile meets the requirements of the U.S. Core Data for Interoperability (USCDI) Medical Device Data Class, including FDA Unique Device Identification (UDI) information associated with a patient's medical device(s). It specifies which core elements, extensions, vocabularies, and value sets SHALL be present in the resource and constrains how the elements are used and provides the floor for standards development for specific use cases promotes interoperability and adoption.

US Core DiagnosticReport Profile for Laboratory Results Reporting

The US Core DiagnosticReport Profile for Laboratory Results Reporting inherits from the FHIR DiagnosticReport resource; refer to it for scope and usage definitions. Laboratory results are grouped and summarized using the DiagnosticReport resource, which typically references Observation resource(s). Each Observation resource represents an individual laboratory test and result value or component result values or a nested panel (such as a microbial susceptibility panel) that references other observations. Laboratory results can also be presented in report form or as free text. This profile sets minimum expectations for the DiagnosticReport resource to record, search, and fetch laboratory results associated with a patient. It specifies which core elements, extensions, vocabularies, and value sets SHALL be present and constrains how the elements are used. Providing the floor for standards development for specific use cases promotes interoperability and adoption.

US Core DiagnosticReport Profile for Report and Note Exchange

The US Core DiagnosticReport Profile for Report and Note Exchange inherits from the FHIR DiagnosticReport resource; refer to it for scope and usage definitions. This profile sets minimum expectations for searching and fetching Diagnostic Reports and Notes using the DiagnosticReport resource. It specifies which core elements, extensions, vocabularies, and value sets SHALL be present in the resource and constrains how the elements are used. Providing the floor for standards development for specific use cases promotes interoperability and adoption. Before reviewing this profile, implementers are encouraged to read the Clinical Notes Guidance to understand the overlap of the US Core DiagnosticReport Profile for Report and Note exchange and the US Core DocumentReference Profile.

US Core Direct email Extension

This email address is associated with a "Direct Secure Messaging" service. This extension can only be used on contact points where the system = 'email'

US Core DocumentReference Profile

The US Core DocumentReference Profile inherits from the FHIR DocumentReference resource; refer to it for scope and usage definitions. This profile sets minimum expectations for searching and fetching patient documents including Clinical Notes using the DocumentReference resource. It specifies which core elements, extensions, vocabularies, and value sets SHALL be present and constrains how the elements are used. Providing the floor for standards development for specific use cases promotes interoperability and adoption. Before reviewing this profile, implementers are encouraged to read the Clinical Notes Guidance to understand the overlap of the US Core DiagnosticReport Profile for Report and Note exchange and the US Core DocumentReference Profile.

US Core Encounter Profile

The US Core Encounter Profile inherits from the FHIR Encounter resource; refer to it for scope and usage definitions. This profile sets minimum expectations for the Encounter resource to record, search, and fetch basic encounter information for an individual patient. It specifies which core elements, extensions, vocabularies, and value sets SHALL be present and constrains how the elements are used. Providing the floor for standards development for specific use cases promotes interoperability and adoption.

US Core Ethnicity Extension

Concepts classifying the person into a named category of humans sharing common history, traits, geographical origin or nationality. The ethnicity codes used to represent these concepts are based upon the Race & Ethnicity - CDC (CDCREC) code system. Detailed ethnicity concepts are grouped by and pre-mapped to the 2 OMB ethnicity categories:

Hispanic or Latino
Not Hispanic or Latino.

US Core Extension Questionnaire URI

The location where a non-FHIR questionnaire/survey form can be found. This extension is used when the survey, form, or questionnaire which is being answered is not a FHIR Questionnaire, otherwise the canonical url for the FHIR Questionnaire is used.

US Core FamilyMemberHistory Profile

The US Core FamilyMemberHistory Profile inherits from the FHIR FamilyMemberHistory resource; refer to it for scope and usage definitions. This profile sets minimum expectations for the FamilyMemberHistory resource to record, search, and retrieve basic clinical information about a family member's health history that is relevant to a patient's care. It specifies which core elements, extensions, vocabularies, and value sets SHALL be present and constrains how the elements are used. Providing the floor for standards development for specific use cases promotes interoperability and adoption.

US Core FamilyMemberHistory Recorder Extension

Individual who recorded the family member's health history and takes responsibility for its content. Because the recorder takes responsibility for accurately recording information in the record, the recorder is the most recent author. The recorder might or might not be the asserter.

US Core Gender Identity Extension

This extension represents an individual's sense of being a man, woman, boy, girl, nonbinary, or something else, ascertained by asking them what that identity is.

US Core Goal Profile

The US Core Goal Profile inherits from the FHIR Goal resource; refer to it for scope and usage definitions. This profile sets minimum expectations for the Goal resource to record, search, and fetch Goal information associated with a patient. It specifies which core elements, extensions, vocabularies, and value sets SHALL be present and constrains how the elements are used. Providing the floor for standards development for specific use cases promotes interoperability and adoption.

US Core Head Circumference Profile

The US Core Head Circumference Profile inherits from the US Core Vital Signs Profile. This profile sets minimum expectations for the Observation resource to record, search, and fetch head circumference observations with a standard LOINC code and UCUM units of measure. It specifies which additional core elements, extensions, vocabularies, and value sets SHALL be present in the resource and constrains how the elements are used. Providing the floor for standards development for specific use cases promotes interoperability and adoption.

US Core Heart Rate Profile

The US Core Heart Rate Profile inherits from the US Core Vital Signs Profile. This profile sets minimum expectations for the Observation resource to record, search, and fetch heart rate observations with a standard LOINC code and UCUM units of measure. It specifies which additional core elements, extensions, vocabularies, and value sets SHALL be present in the resource and constrains how the elements are used. Providing the floor for standards development for specific use cases promotes interoperability and adoption.

US Core Immunization Profile

The US Core Immunization Profile inherits from the FHIR Immunization resource; refer to it for scope and usage definitions. This profile sets minimum expectations for the Immunization resource to record, search, and fetch immunization history associated with a patient. It specifies which core elements, extensions, vocabularies, and value sets SHALL be present and constrains how the elements are used. Providing the floor for standards development for specific use cases promotes interoperability and adoption.

US Core Individual Sex Extension

USCDI includes a data element for Sex, intended to support the exchange of a recorded sex value. This extension aligns with the USCDI definition of Sex: "Documentation of a specific instance of sex." It enables systems to share the sex value as it was documented in a particular context. Systems choosing to record sources of information should use the Provenance resource.

US Core Interpreter Needed Extension

This extension indicates the individual's need for an interpreter to communicate healthcare information in a language other than the default language of the organization. It has the same meaning as the LOINC 54588-9 (Interpreter needed)

US Core Jurisdiction Extension

An extension to communicate the US state or local jurisdiction for individual and entity identifiers. For example, a practitioner's state or local jurisdiction for a license.

US Core Laboratory Result Observation Profile

The US Core Laboratory Result Observation Profile is based upon the US Core Observation Clinical Result Profile and, along with the US Core DiagnosticReport Profile for Laboratory Results Reporting, meets the U.S. Core Data for Interoperability (USCDI) Laboratory requirements. Laboratory results are grouped and summarized using the DiagnosticReport resource, which references Observation resources. Each Observation resource represents an individual laboratory test and result value, a “nested” panel (such as a microbial susceptibility panel) that references other observations, or rarely a laboratory test with component result values. The US Core Laboratory Result Observation Profile sets minimum expectations for the Observation resource to record, search, and fetch laboratory test results associated with a patient to promote interoperability and adoption through common implementation. It identifies which core elements, extensions, vocabularies, and value sets SHALL be present in the resource and constrains the way the elements are used when using this profile. It provides the floor for standards development for specific use cases.

US Core Location Profile

The US Core Location Profile inherits from the FHIR Location resource; refer to it for scope and usage definitions. This profile sets minimum expectations for the Location resource for recording, searching, and fetching a "physical place of available services or resources." It specifies which core elements, extensions, vocabularies, and value sets SHALL be present and constrains how the elements are used. Providing the floor for standards development for specific use cases promotes interoperability and adoption.

US Core Medication Adherence Extension

The Medication Adherence Extension is used to report whether a medication has been consumed according to instructions as reported by a patient or on behalf of the patient.

US Core MedicationDispense Profile

The US Core MedicationDispense Profile inherits from the FHIR MedicationDispense resource; refer to it for scope and usage definitions. This profile sets minimum expectations for the MedicationDispense resource to record, search, and fetch the state of a patients medication with regards to dispensing or other activity. (e.g., dispensed, partially dispensed, not dispensed) It specifies which core elements, extensions, vocabularies, and value sets SHALL be present and constrains how the elements are used. Providing the floor for standards development for specific use cases promotes interoperability and adoption.

US Core Medication Profile

The US Core Medication Profile inherits from the FHIR Medication resource; refer to it for scope and usage definitions. This profile sets minimum expectations for the Medication resource to record, search, and fetch medications associated with a patient. When referencing a medication, the MedicationRequest resource can use a code or refer to this profile. It specifies which core elements, extensions, vocabularies, and value sets SHALL be present and constrains how the elements are used. Providing the floor for standards development for specific use cases promotes interoperability and adoption.

US Core MedicationRequest Profile

The US Core MedicationRequest Profile inherits from the FHIR MedicationRequest resource; refer to it for scope and usage definitions. This profile meets the requirements of the U.S. Core Data for Interoperability (USCDI) Medications Data Class. This profile sets minimum expectations for the MedicationRequest resource to record, search, and fetch a patient's medication prescriptions or orders. It specifies which core elements, extensions, vocabularies, and value sets SHALL be present in the resource and constrains how the elements are used. Providing the floor for standards development for specific use cases promotes interoperability and adoption.

US Core Observation ADI Documentation Profile

The US Core Observation Advance Directive Information (ADI) Documentation Profile inherits from the FHIR Observation resource; refer to it for scope and usage definitions. This profile and the US Core Observation ADI DocumentationReference Profile meet the U.S. Core Data for Interoperability (USCDI) Advance Directive Observation Data Element requirements. It is used to communicate whether a person has advance directive information (ADI) and, if one or more documents exist, their location. Examples of advance healthcare directive documents include physician order for life sustaining treatment (POLST), do not resuscitate order (DNR), and medical power of attorney. To communicate the type of advance directive document, the author, the verifier, and other properties, see the US Core ADI DocumentReference Profile. This profile sets minimum expectations for the Observation resource to record, search, and fetch findings about the presence of a patient's advance directives. It specifies which core elements, extensions, vocabularies, and value sets SHALL be present in the resource and constrains how the elements are used. Providing the floor for standards development for specific use cases promotes interoperability and adoption.

US Core Observation Clinical Result Profile

The US Core Observation Clinical Result Profile is based upon the core FHIR Observation Resource and, along with the US Core DiagnosticReport Profile, meets the US Core Data for Interoperability (USCDI) requirements for Diagnostic Imaging and Clinical Tests Data Classes. This profile sets minimum expectations for the Observation resource to record and search non-laboratory clinical test results (e.g., radiology and other clinical observations generated from procedures). An example would be when a gastroenterologist reports the size of a polyp observed during a colonoscopy. This profile is the basis for the US Core Laboratory Result Observation Profile, which defines additional data elements to record and search laboratory test results.

The US Core Observation Clinical Result Profile sets minimum expectations to promote interoperability and adoption through common implementation. It identifies which core elements, extensions, vocabularies, and value sets SHALL be present in the resource and constrains the way the elements are used when using this profile. It provides the floor for standards development for specific use cases.

US Core Observation Occupation Profile

The US Core Observation Occupation Profile inherits from the FHIR Observation resource; refer to it for scope and usage definitions. This profile meets the requirements of the U.S. Core Data for Interoperability (USCDI) Occupation and Occupation Industry Data Elements. It sets minimum expectations for the Observation resource to record, search, and fetch a patient's past or present job as occupation and industry, in other words, the type of work and type of business that compensates for work or assigns work to an unpaid worker or volunteer. In the context of this profile, a job is defined as a work situation or a training or volunteer position held for a specified period. This profile specifies which core elements, extensions, vocabularies, and value sets SHALL be present in the resource and constrains how the elements are used. Providing the floor for standards development for specific use cases promotes interoperability and adoption.

US Core Observation Pregnancy Intent Profile

The US Core Observation Pregnancy Intent Profile inherits from the FHIR Observation resource; refer to it for scope and usage definitions. This profile meets the requirements of the U.S. Core Data for Interoperability (USCDI) Pregnancy Status Data Element. This profile sets minimum expectations for the Observation resource to record, search, and fetch the patient's intention to become pregnant. It specifies which core elements, extensions, vocabularies, and value sets SHALL be present in the resource and constrains how the elements are used. Providing the floor for standards development for specific use cases promotes interoperability and adoption.

US Core Observation Pregnancy Status Profile

The US Core Pregnancy Status Observation Profile inherits from the FHIR Observation resource; refer to it for scope and usage definitions. This profile meets the requirements of the U.S. Core Data for Interoperability (USCDI) Pregnancy Status Data Element. It sets minimum expectations for the Observation resource to record, search, and fetch the patient's state or condition of being pregnant. It specifies which core elements, extensions, vocabularies, and value sets SHALL be present in the resource and constrains how the elements are used. Providing the floor for standards development for specific use cases promotes interoperability and adoption.

US Core Observation Screening Assessment Profile

The US Core Observation Screening Assessment Profile inherits from the FHIR Observation resource; refer to it for scope and usage definitions. Beginning with US Core Version 6.0.0, this profile supersedes the US Core Observation Survey Profile (see the Changes Between Versions page for a summary of cross-version comparisons of US Core Profiles). This profile meets the requirements of the U.S. Core Data for Interoperability (USCDI) Health Status Assessments Data Class. It sets the minimum expectations for the Observation Resource to record, search, and fetch observations representing the questions and responses to surveys and screening and assessment tools. For example, a social history status such as education or food insecurity or an assessment of cognitive, functional, or disability status. It can represent a single response, multiple responses, and multi-select "check all that apply" type questions. This profile specifies which core elements, extensions, vocabularies, and value sets SHALL be present in the resource and constrains how the elements are used. Providing the floor for standards development for specific use cases promotes interoperability and adoption. Before reviewing this profile, implementers are encouraged to read the Screening and Assessments guidance page, which documents the process of recording responses and capturing assertions/determinations resulting from surveys and questionnaires.

US Core Observation Sexual Orientation Profile

The US Core Observation Sexual Orientation Profile inherits from the FHIR Observation resource; refer to it for scope and usage definitions. This Profile sets minimum expectations for the Observation resource to record, search, and fetch sexual orientation observations associated with a patient. It specifies which core elements, extensions, vocabularies, and value sets SHALL be present in the resource and constrains how the elements are used. Providing the floor for standards development for specific use cases promotes interoperability and adoption.

US Core Organization Profile

The US Core Organization Profile inherits from the FHIR Organization resource; refer to it for scope and usage definitions. This profile sets minimum expectations for the Organization resource to record, search, and fetch patient or provider organization information. It specifies which core elements, extensions, vocabularies, and value sets SHALL be present and constrains how the elements are used. Providing the floor for standards development for specific use cases promotes interoperability and adoption.

US Core Patient Profile

The US Core Patient Profile inherits from the FHIR Patient resource; refer to it for scope and usage definitions. This profile meets the requirements of the U.S. Core Data for Interoperability (USCDI) Patient Demographics/Information Data Class. It sets minimum expectations for the Patient resource to record, search, and fetch basic demographics and other administrative information about an individual patient. It specifies which core elements, extensions, vocabularies, and value sets SHALL be present and constrains how the elements are used. Providing the floor for standards development for specific use cases promotes interoperability and adoption.

US Core Pediatric BMI for Age Observation Profile

The US Core Pediatric BMI for Age Observation Profile inherits from the US Core Vital Signs Profile. This profile sets minimum expectations for the Observation resource to record, search, and fetch pediatric body mass index (BMI) percentile per age and sex for youth 2-20 observations in FHIR using a standard LOINC code and UCUM units of measure. It specifies which additional core elements, extensions, vocabularies, and value sets SHALL be present in the resource and constrains how the elements are used. Providing the floor for standards development for specific use cases promotes interoperability and adoption.

US Core Pediatric Head Occipital Frontal Circumference Percentile Profile

The US Core Pediatric Head Occipital Frontal Circumference Percentile Profile inherits from the US Core Vital Signs Profile. This profile sets minimum expectations for the Observation resource to record, search, and fetch pediatric head occipital frontal circumference (OFC) percentile observations associated with a patient from birth to 37 Months of age using a standard LOINC code and UCUM units of measure. It specifies which additional core elements, extensions, vocabularies, and value sets SHALL be present in the resource and constrains how the elements are used. Providing the floor for standards development for specific use cases promotes interoperability and adoption.

US Core Pediatric Weight for Height Observation Profile

US Core Pediatric Weight for Height Observation Profile inherits from the US Core Vital Signs Profile. This profile sets minimum expectations for the Observation resource to record, search, and fetch pediatric weight-for-length per age and sex observations in FHIR with a standard LOINC code and UCUM units of measure. It specifies which additional core elements, extensions, vocabularies, and value sets SHALL be present in the resource and constrains how the elements are used. Providing the floor for standards development for specific use cases promotes interoperability and adoption.

US Core Practitioner Profile

The US Core Practitioner Profile inherits from the FHIR Practitioner resource; refer to it for scope and usage definitions. This profile sets minimum expectations for the Practitioner resource to record, search, and fetch basic demographics and administrative information about an individual practitioner. It specifies which core elements, extensions, vocabularies, and value sets SHALL be present and constrains how the elements are used. Providing the floor for standards development for specific use cases promotes interoperability and adoption.

US Core PractitionerRole Profile

The US Core PractitionerRole Profile inherits from the FHIR PractitionerRole resource; refer to it for scope and usage definitions. This profile sets minimum expectations for the PractitionerRole Resource to record, search, and fetch the practitioner role information. It specifies which core elements, extensions, vocabularies, and value sets SHALL be present and constrains how the elements are used. Providing the floor for standards development for specific use cases promotes interoperability and adoption. The requirements for the US Core Practitioner were drawn from the Argonaut Provider Directory, IHE Healthcare Provider Directory and the ONC Provider Directory Workshop.

US Core Procedure Profile

The US Core Procedure Profile inherits from the FHIR Procedure resource; refer to it for scope and usage definitions. This profile meets the requirements of the U.S. Core Data for Interoperability (USCDI) Procedures Data Class. It sets minimum expectations for the Procedure resource to record, search, and fetch procedure information associated with a patient. It specifies which core elements, extensions, vocabularies, and value sets SHALL be present and constrains how the elements are used. Providing the floor for standards development for specific use cases promotes interoperability and adoption.

US Core Provenance Profile

The US Core Provenance Profile inherits from the FHIR Provenance resource; refer to it for scope and usage definitions. This profile sets minimum expectations for the Provenance resource to record, search, and fetch provenance information associated with a record. It covers the minimal (basic) information to support lineage of information. It specifies which core elements, extensions, vocabularies, and value sets SHALL be present and constrains how the elements are used. Before reviewing this profile, implementers are encouraged to read the Basic Provenance guidance page, which documents several key use cases, specifically, the organization responsible for the most recent action on the resource.

US Core Pulse Oximetry Profile

The US Core Pulse Oximetry Profile inherits from the US Core Vital Signs Profile. This profile sets minimum expectations for the Observation resource to record, search, and fetch pulse oximetry and inspired oxygen observations with standard LOINC codes and UCUM units of measure. It specifies which additional core elements, extensions, vocabularies, and value sets SHALL be present in the resource and constrains how the elements are used. Providing the floor for standards development for specific use cases promotes interoperability and adoption.

US Core QuestionnaireResponse Profile

The US Core QuestionnaireResponse Profile inherits from the Structured Data Capture (SDC) Questionnaire Response Profile. This profile sets minimum expectations for the QuestionnaireResponse resource to record, search, and fetch the responses to form/survey and assessment tools such as the Protocol for Responding to and Assessing Patients\u2019 Assets, Risks, and Experiences (PRAPARE) Survey. It specifies which core additional elements, extensions, vocabularies, and value sets SHALL be present and constrains how the elements are used. Before reviewing this profile, implementers are encouraged to read the Screening and Assessments guidance page, which documents the process of recording responses and capturing assertions/determinations resulting from surveys and questionnaires.

US Core Race Extension

Concepts classifying the person into a named category of humans sharing common history, traits, geographical origin or nationality. The race codes used to represent these concepts are based upon the Race & Ethnicity - CDC (CDCREC) code system. Detailed race concepts are grouped by and pre-mapped to the 5 OMB race categories:

American Indian or Alaska Native
Asian
Black or African American
Native Hawaiian or Other Pacific Islander
White.

US Core RelatedPerson Profile

The US Core RelatedPerson Profile inherits from the FHIR RelatedPerson resource; refer to it for scope and usage definitions. This profile sets minimum expectations for the RelatedPerson resource to record, search, and fetch basic administrative information about persons with a legal or familial relationship to a patient. It specifies which core elements, extensions, vocabularies, and value sets SHALL be present and constrains how the elements are used. Providing the floor for standards development for specific use cases promotes interoperability and adoption.

US Core Respiratory Rate Profile

The US Core Respiratory Rate Profile inherits from the US Core Vital Signs Profile. This profile sets minimum expectations for the Observation resource to record, search, and fetch respiratory rate observations with a standard LOINC code and UCUM units of measure. It specifies which additional core elements, extensions, vocabularies, and value sets SHALL be present in the resource and constrains how the elements are used. Providing the floor for standards development for specific use cases promotes interoperability and adoption.

US Core ServiceRequest Profile

The US Core ServiceRequest Profile inherits from the FHIR ServiceRequest resource; refer to it for scope and usage definitions. This profile sets minimum expectations for recording, searching, and fetching the ServiceRequest information. It specifies which core elements, extensions, vocabularies, and value sets SHALL be present and constrains how the elements are used. Providing the floor for standards development for specific use cases promotes interoperability and adoption.

US Core Sex Extension

The Sex Extension is used to reflect the documentation of a person's sex. Systems choosing to record sources of information should use the Provenance resource.

USCDI includes a data element for sex, intended to support the exchange of a sex value that is not characterized as sex assigned at birth or birth sex. This Sex extension supports USCDI. Sex assigned at birth or birth sex can be recorded using the more specific US Core Birth Sex Extension. Future versions of this extension may be informed by the content of the HL7 Cross Paradigm IG: Gender Harmony - Sex and Gender Representation, which may include additional guidance on its relationship to administrative gender (Patient.gender).

US Core Simple Observation Profile

The US Core Simple Observation Profile inherits from the FHIR Observation resource; refer to it for scope and usage definitions. This US Core FHIR Profile captures any "simple" observations not covered by other US Core Observation profiles. It represents any observation not classified as vital signs, laboratory, imaging, or other specific observation types. This profile sets minimum expectations for the Observation resource to record, search, and retrieve observations such as a clinical observation or assertion about patient health status or other general observations. It specifies which core elements, extensions, vocabularies, and value sets SHALL be present and constrains how the elements are used. Providing the floor for standards development for specific use cases promotes interoperability and adoption.

US Core Smoking Status Observation Profile

The US Core Smoking Status Observation Profile inherits from the FHIR Observation resource; refer to it for scope and usage definitions. This profile meets the requirements of the U.S. Core Data for Interoperability (USCDI) Smoking Status Data Element. This profile sets minimum expectations for the Observation resource to record, search, and fetch smoking status data associated with a patient. It specifies which core elements, extensions, vocabularies, and value sets SHALL be present in the resource and constrains how the elements are used. Providing the floor for standards development for specific use cases promotes interoperability and adoption.

US Core Specimen Profile

The US Core Specimen Profile inherits from the FHIR Specimen resource; refer to it for scope and usage definitions. This profile sets minimum expectations for the Specimen resource to record, search, and fetch information about substances associated with a patient being sampled or tested (such as nasopharyngeal swab, whole blood, or serum). It specifies which core elements, extensions, vocabularies, and value sets SHALL be present and constrains how the elements are used. Providing the floor for standards development for specific use cases promotes interoperability and adoption.

US Core Treatment Intervention Preference Profile

The US Core Treatment Intervention Preference Profile inherits from the FHIR Observation resource; refer to it for scope and usage definitions. This profile provides guidance on how to record a treatment intervention preference expressed by the patient regarding their personal health goals, preferences, and priorities for medical treatments or interventions in the event of a future health scenario where a person is unable to make medical decisions because of a severe illness or injury. This profile does not represent an actual order, but it can guide caregivers and medical personnel about what is important for the person. This profile sets minimum expectations for the Observation resource to record, search, and fetch for patient treatment intervention preferences. It specifies which core elements, extensions, vocabularies, and value sets SHALL be present in the resource and constrains how the elements are used. Providing the floor for standards development for specific use cases promotes interoperability and adoption.

US Core Tribal Affiliation Extension

This Extension profile represents a tribe or band with which a person associates and, optionally, whether they are enrolled.

US Core Vital Signs Profile

This profile is based on the base FHIR Vital Signs Profile and defines additional constraints on the Observation resource to represent vital signs observations. It specifies which core elements, extensions, vocabularies, and value sets SHALL be present in the resource and constrains how the elements are used. Providing the floor for standards development for specific use cases promotes interoperability and adoption. This US Core profiles that are derived from this profile are listed below.

{% endraw %}

{% raw %} US Core Narrative Status

The US Core Narrative Status Value Set limits the text status for the resource narrative.

US Core Clinical Note Type

The US Core Clinical Note Type Value Set is a 'starter set' of types supported for fetching and storing clinical notes.

US Core Clinical Result Observation Category

Used to classify the context of clinical result observations.

US Core Condition Codes

This describes the problem. Diagnosis/Problem List is broadly defined as a series of brief statements that catalog a patient's medical, nursing, dental, social, preventative and psychiatric events and issues that are relevant to that patient's healthcare (e.g., signs, symptoms, and defined conditions). ICD-10 is appropriate for Diagnosis information, and ICD-9 for historical information.

US Core Diagnostic Report Category Codes

The US Core Diagnostic Report Category Value Set is a 'starter set' of categories supported for fetching and Diagnostic Reports and notes.

US Core DocumentReference Category

The US Core DocumentReferences Category Value Set is a 'starter set' of categories supported for fetching and storing clinical notes.

US Core DocumentReference Type

The US Core DocumentReference Type Value Set includes all LOINC values whose SCALE is "Doc" in the LOINC database and the HL7 v3 Code System NullFlavor concept 'unknown'

US Core Goal Codes

Concepts from SNOMED CT and LOINC code systems that can be used to indicate the goal.

US Core Laboratory Test Codes

Laboratory LOINC codes: From the introduction to August 2022 LOINC Users' guide; "The current scope of the existing laboratory portion of the LOINC database includes all observations reported by clinical laboratories, including the specialty areas: chemistry, including therapeutic drug monitoring and toxicology; hematology; serology; blood bank; microbiology; cytology; surgical pathology; and fertility.

US Core Location Type Codes

This value set represents the types of locations and organizational settings where healthcare services, encounters, or treatments occur, and is composed of several value sets to meet multiple industry needs. It includes HL7 Terminology (THO), SNOMED CT, National Healthcare Safety Network (NHSN), and CMS Place of Service Codes (POS) concepts.

US Core Non Laboratory Codes

This value set includes All LOINC codes defined as type "clinical," therefore excluding laboratory tests, survey instruments, and claims documents. This includes observables such as vital signs, hemodynamics, intake/output, EKG, obstetric ultrasound, and cardiac echo, and includes discrete and narrative diagnostic observations and reports.

US Core Status for Smoking Status Observation

Codes providing the status of an observation for smoking status. Constrained to final and entered-in-error.

US Core Practitioner Role Specialty Codes

This value set represents the clinical specialty or functional role played by a clinician or provider. It is composed of two value sets, and include the National Uniform Claims Committee (NUCC) and SNOMED CT concepts.

US Core Problem or Health Concern

Code set for category codes for US Core Condition Problems and Health Concerns Profile consisting of the concepts "problem" and "health-concern".

US Core Procedure Codes

Concepts from CPT, SNOMED CT, HCPCS Level II Alphanumeric Codes, ICD-10-PCS, CDT and LOINC code systems that can be used to indicate the type of procedure performed.

US Core Screening Assessment Condition Category

This value set consists of the single code "sdoh". It is the minimum value set of category codes used in the US Core Condition Problems and Health Concerns Profile that any conformant system SHALL support to help identify the type of USCDI Health Status/Assessment data class being reported.

US Core Screening Assessment Observation Category

This value set is the minimum value set of category codes used in the US Core Observation Screening Assessment and Simple Observation Profiles that any conformant system SHALL support to help identify the type of USCDI Health Status/Assessment data class being reported.

US Core Screening Assessment Observation Maximum Category

This value set is a value set of category codes used in the US Core Observation Screening Assessment that any conformant system SHOULD support to help identify the type of USCDI Health Status/Assessment data class being reported.

US Core ServiceRequest Category Codes

A set of SNOMED CT and LOINC concepts to classify a requested service

US Core Simple Observation Category

This value set is a value set of category codes used in the US Core Simple Observation and Condition Problems and Health Concerns Profiles that any conformant system SHOULD support to help identify the type of USCDI Health Status/Assessment data class being reported.

US Core Specimen Condition

This value set contains concepts the provide information regarding a specimen, including the container, that does not meet a laboratory’s criteria for acceptability.

{% endraw %}

{% raw %} US Core Fetch DocumentReference

This operation is used to return all the references to documents related to a patient. It is invoked on a FHIR Server's DocumentReference endpoint (e.g., [base]/DocumentReference/$docref) and operates across all DocumentReference instances.

The operation requires a patient id and takes the optional input parameters:

start context date
end context date
document type
on-demand
profile

and returns a searchset Bundle containing DocumentReference resources for the patient. If the server has stored documents or can create documents for the patient and those documents are available for the user, the server returns the DocumentReference resources associated with documents. This operation's intended use is to provide a way for providers or patients to access their available documents. The document itself can be subsequently retrieved using the link provided in the DocumentReference.content.attachment.url element. The link could be a FHIR endpoint to a Binary Resource or some other document repository.

This operation is different from a FHIR RESTful query on DocumentReference by patient and type and period range because:

It is used to request a server to generate a document based on the specified parameters.

If no parameters are specified, the server SHALL return a DocumentReference to the patient's current C-CDA CCD.

If the server cannot generate a document based on the specified parameters, the operation will return an empty search bundle.

Unless the client indicates they are only interested in 'on-demand' documents using the on-demand parameter, the server SHOULD return DocumentReference instances for existing documents that meet the request parameters In this regard, this operation is similar to a FHIR RESTful query.

{% endraw %}

{% raw %}

Defining URL: | http://hl7.org/fhir/us/core/Questionnaire/prapare-example
Version: | 9.0.0
Name: | PRAPAREExample
Title: | Protocol for Responding to and Assessing Patients' Assets, Risks, and Experiences [PRAPARE]
Status: | Experimental as of 2023-03-31
Publisher: | HL7 International / Cross-Group Projects. HL7 International / Cross-Group Projects, , Email
Copyright: |

This material contains content from LOINC® (http://loinc.org). LOINC is copyright © 1995-2024, Regenstrief Institute, Inc. and the LOINC Committee, and is available at no cost under the license at http://loinc.org/license. Copyright © 2019. This item comes from the national PRAPARE social determinants of health assessment protocol, developed and owned by the National Association of Community Health Centers (NACHC), in partnership with the Association of Asian Pacific Community Health Organization (AAPCHO), the Oregon Primary Care Association (OPCA), and the Institute for Alternative Futures (IAF). For more information, visit www.nachc.org/prapare. Used with permission.

Source Resource: | XML / JSON / Turtle

{% endraw %}

{% raw %}

Defining URL: | http://hl7.org/fhir/us/core/StructureDefinition/us-core-adi-documentreference
Version: | 9.0.0
Name: | USCoreADIDocumentReferenceProfile
Title: | US Core ADI DocumentReference Profile
Status: | Active as of 2023-10-17 (Standards Status: Trial Use)
Definition: |

The US Core Advance Directive Information (ADI) DocumentReference Profile inherits from the FHIR DocumentReference resource; refer to it for scope and usage definitions. It sets minimum expectations for searching and fetching patient Advance Directive Information (ADI) documents using the DocumentReference resource. Examples of advance healthcare directive documents include physician order for life sustaining treatment (POLST), do not resuscitate order (DNR), and Living Will. In addition to the document contents, it communicates the type of advance directive document, the author, the verifier, and other properties. To represent whether advance directive documents exist for a patient, see the US Core Observation ADI Documentation Profile. This profile sets minimum expectations for searching and fetching patient ADI documents using the DocumentReference resource. It specifies which core elements, extensions, vocabularies, and value sets SHALL be present and constrains how the elements are used. Providing the floor for standards development for specific use cases promotes interoperability and adoption.

Publisher: | HL7 International / Cross-Group Projects. HL7 International / Cross-Group Projects, , Email
Committee: | Cross-Group Projects
Maturity: | 2
Source Resource: | XML / JSON / Turtle

{% endraw %}

{% raw %}

Defining URL: | http://hl7.org/fhir/us/core/StructureDefinition/us-core-diagnosticreport-lab
Version: | 9.0.0
Name: | USCoreDiagnosticReportProfileLaboratoryReporting
Title: | US Core DiagnosticReport Profile for Laboratory Results Reporting
Status: | Active as of 2023-10-17 (Standards Status: Trial Use)
Definition: |

The US Core DiagnosticReport Profile for Laboratory Results Reporting inherits from the FHIR DiagnosticReport resource; refer to it for scope and usage definitions. Laboratory results are grouped and summarized using the DiagnosticReport resource, which typically references Observation resource(s). Each Observation resource represents an individual laboratory test and result value or component result values or a nested panel (such as a microbial susceptibility panel) that references other observations. Laboratory results can also be presented in report form or as free text. This profile sets minimum expectations for the DiagnosticReport resource to record, search, and fetch laboratory results associated with a patient. It specifies which core elements, extensions, vocabularies, and value sets SHALL be present and constrains how the elements are used. Providing the floor for standards development for specific use cases promotes interoperability and adoption.

Publisher: | HL7 International / Cross-Group Projects. HL7 International / Cross-Group Projects, , Email
Committee: | Cross-Group Projects
Maturity: | 5
Source Resource: | XML / JSON / Turtle

{% endraw %}

{% raw %}

Name | Type | Description | Expression
address | string |

A (part of the) address of the location
NOTE: This SearchParameter is defined only to document Server and Client expectations. Its definition is derived from the standard FHIR SearchParameter and it uses the Conformance expectation extension to define additional expectations for the following SearchParameter elements:

multipleAnd
multipleOr
comparator
modifier
chain

It SHALL NOT be used as a search parameter for search. Servers and Clients SHOULD use the standard FHIR SearchParameter.

| Location.address
address-city | string |

A city specified in an address

| Location.address.city
address-country | string |

A country specified in an address

| Location.address.country
address-postalcode | string |

A postal code specified in an address
NOTE: This SearchParameter is defined only to document Server and Client expectations. Its definition is derived from the standard FHIR SearchParameter and it uses the Conformance expectation extension to define additional expectations for the following SearchParameter elements:

multipleAnd
multipleOr
comparator
modifier
chain

It SHALL NOT be used as a search parameter for search. Servers and Clients SHOULD use the standard FHIR SearchParameter.

| Location.address.postalCode
address-state | string |

A state specified in an address

| Location.address.state
address-use | token |

A use code specified in an address

| Location.address.use
endpoint | reference |

Technical endpoints providing access to services operated for the location

| Location.endpoint
identifier | token |

An identifier for the location

| Location.identifier
name | string |

A portion of the location's name or alias
NOTE: This SearchParameter is defined only to document Server and Client expectations. Its definition is derived from the standard FHIR SearchParameter and it uses the Conformance expectation extension to define additional expectations for the following SearchParameter elements:

multipleAnd
multipleOr
comparator
modifier
chain

It SHALL NOT be used as a search parameter for search. Servers and Clients SHOULD use the standard FHIR SearchParameter.

| Location.name|Location.alias
near | special |

Search for locations where the location.position is near to, or within a specified distance of, the provided coordinates expressed as [latitude]|[longitude]|[distance]|[units] (using the WGS84 datum, see notes). If the units are omitted, then kms should be assumed. If the distance is omitted, then the server can use its own discretion as to what distances should be considered near (and units are irrelevant)

Servers may search using various techniques that might have differing accuracies, depending on implementation efficiency.

Requires the near-distance parameter to be provided also

| Location.position
operational-status | token |

Searches for locations (typically bed/room) that have an operational status (e.g. contaminated, housekeeping)

| Location.operationalStatus
organization | reference |

Searches for locations that are managed by the provided organization

| Location.managingOrganization
partof | reference |

A location of which this location is a part

| Location.partOf
status | token |

Searches for locations with a specific kind of status

| Location.status
type | token |

A code for the type of location

| Location.type

{% endraw %}

{% raw %}

Defining URL: | http://hl7.org/fhir/us/core/StructureDefinition/us-core-observation-adi-documentation
Version: | 9.0.0
Name: | USCoreObservationADIDocumentationProfile
Title: | US Core Observation ADI Documentation Profile
Status: | Active as of 2024-09-13 (Standards Status: Trial Use)
Definition: |

The US Core Observation Advance Directive Information (ADI) Documentation Profile inherits from the FHIR Observation resource; refer to it for scope and usage definitions. This profile and the US Core Observation ADI DocumentationReference Profile meet the U.S. Core Data for Interoperability (USCDI) Advance Directive Observation Data Element requirements. It is used to communicate whether a person has advance directive information (ADI) and, if one or more documents exist, their location. Examples of advance healthcare directive documents include physician order for life sustaining treatment (POLST), do not resuscitate order (DNR), and medical power of attorney. To communicate the type of advance directive document, the author, the verifier, and other properties, see the US Core ADI DocumentReference Profile. This profile sets minimum expectations for the Observation resource to record, search, and fetch findings about the presence of a patient's advance directives. It specifies which core elements, extensions, vocabularies, and value sets SHALL be present in the resource and constrains how the elements are used. Providing the floor for standards development for specific use cases promotes interoperability and adoption.

Publisher: | HL7 International / Cross-Group Projects. HL7 International / Cross-Group Projects, , Email
Committee: | Cross-Group Projects
Copyright: |

Used by permission of HL7 International, all rights reserved Creative Commons License

Maturity: | 2
Source Resource: | XML / JSON / Turtle

{% endraw %}

{% raw %}

Defining URL: | http://hl7.org/fhir/us/core/StructureDefinition/us-core-observation-clinical-result
Version: | 9.0.0
Name: | USCoreObservationClinicalResultProfile
Title: | US Core Observation Clinical Result Profile
Status: | Active as of 2023-10-17 (Standards Status: Trial Use)
Definition: |

The US Core Observation Clinical Result Profile is based upon the core FHIR Observation Resource and, along with the US Core DiagnosticReport Profile, meets the US Core Data for Interoperability (USCDI) requirements for Diagnostic Imaging and Clinical Tests Data Classes. This profile sets minimum expectations for the Observation resource to record and search non-laboratory clinical test results (e.g., radiology and other clinical observations generated from procedures). An example would be when a gastroenterologist reports the size of a polyp observed during a colonoscopy. This profile is the basis for the US Core Laboratory Result Observation Profile, which defines additional data elements to record and search laboratory test results.

The US Core Observation Clinical Result Profile sets minimum expectations to promote interoperability and adoption through common implementation. It identifies which core elements, extensions, vocabularies, and value sets SHALL be present in the resource and constrains the way the elements are used when using this profile. It provides the floor for standards development for specific use cases.

Publisher: | HL7 International / Cross-Group Projects. HL7 International / Cross-Group Projects, , Email
Committee: | Cross-Group Projects
Maturity: | 4
Source Resource: | XML / JSON / Turtle

{% endraw %}

{% raw %}

Defining URL: | http://hl7.org/fhir/us/core/StructureDefinition/us-core-observation-screening-assessment
Version: | 9.0.0
Name: | USCoreObservationScreeningAssessmentProfile
Title: | US Core Observation Screening Assessment Profile
Status: | Active as of 2024-11-16 (Standards Status: Trial Use)
Definition: |

The US Core Observation Screening Assessment Profile inherits from the FHIR Observation resource; refer to it for scope and usage definitions. Beginning with US Core Version 6.0.0, this profile supersedes the US Core Observation Survey Profile (see the Changes Between Versions page for a summary of cross-version comparisons of US Core Profiles). This profile meets the requirements of the U.S. Core Data for Interoperability (USCDI) Health Status Assessments Data Class. It sets the minimum expectations for the Observation Resource to record, search, and fetch observations representing the questions and responses to surveys and screening and assessment tools. For example, a social history status such as education or food insecurity or an assessment of cognitive, functional, or disability status. It can represent a single response, multiple responses, and multi-select "check all that apply" type questions. This profile specifies which core elements, extensions, vocabularies, and value sets SHALL be present in the resource and constrains how the elements are used. Providing the floor for standards development for specific use cases promotes interoperability and adoption. Before reviewing this profile, implementers are encouraged to read the Screening and Assessments guidance page, which documents the process of recording responses and capturing assertions/determinations resulting from surveys and questionnaires.

Publisher: | HL7 International / Cross-Group Projects. HL7 International / Cross-Group Projects, , Email
Committee: | Cross-Group Projects
Maturity: | 3
Source Resource: | XML / JSON / Turtle

{% endraw %}

{% raw %}

This profile includes IP covered under the following statements.

"Material on this site is the copyrighted property of the United States Postal Service® (Postal Service™). All rights reserved. The information and images presented here may not under any circumstances be reproduced or used without prior written permission. Users may view and download material from this site only for the following purposes: (a) for personal, non-commercial home use; (b) where the materials clearly state that these materials may be copied and reproduced according to the terms stated in those particular pages; or (c) with the express written permission of the Postal Service. In all other cases, you will need written permission from the Postal Service to reproduce, republish, upload, post, transmit, distribute or publicly display material from this Web site. Users agree not to use the site for sale, trade or other commercial purposes. Users may not use language that is threatening, abusive, vulgar, discourteous or criminal. Users also may not post or transmit information or materials that would violate rights of any third party or which contains a virus or other harmful component. The Postal Service reserves the right to remove or edit any messages or material submitted by users."For more information, see https://about.usps.com/who/legal/terms-of-use.htm .

Show Usage

USPS State Codes: USCorePractitionerProfile

ISO maintains the copyright on the country codes, and controls its use carefully. For further details see the ISO 3166 web page: https://www.iso.org/iso-3166-country-codes.html

Show Usage

ISO 3166-1 Codes for the representation of names of countries and their subdivisions — Part 1: Country code: USCorePractitionerProfile

{% endraw %}

{% raw %} US Core Certifying System Requirements |

This Requirements resource lists the additional requirements for systems certifying for Office of the National Coordinator for Health Information Technology (ONC) Health IT Certification (g(10) certification. These requirements represent the regulatory and technical specifications that design artifacts must meet to ensure interoperability. See the US Core Server Requirements for the US Core Responder (Server) requirements defined in the US Core Implementation Guide narrative sections.

US Core Client Requirements |

This Requirements resource lists the US Core Requestor (Client) requirements defined in the US Core Implementation Guide narrative sections. These requirements represent the regulatory, business, functional, and technical specifications that design artifacts must meet to ensure interoperability.

US Core Server Requirements |

This Requirements resource lists the US Core Responder (Server) requirements defined in the US Core Implementation Guide narrative sections. These requirements represent the regulatory, business, functional, and technical specifications that design artifacts must meet to ensure interoperability. See the US Core Certifying System Requirements for the additional requirements for systems certifying for Office of the National Coordinator for Health Information Technology (ONC) Health IT Certification (g)(10) certification.

{% endraw %}

{% raw %} US Core Clinical Note Type |

The US Core Clinical Note Type Value Set is a 'starter set' of types supported for fetching and storing clinical notes.

US Core Clinical Result Observation Category |

Used to classify the context of clinical result observations.

US Core Diagnostic Report Category Codes |

The US Core Diagnostic Report Category Value Set is a 'starter set' of categories supported for fetching and Diagnostic Reports and notes.

US Core Non Laboratory Codes |

This value set includes All LOINC codes defined as type "clinical," therefore excluding laboratory tests, survey instruments, and claims documents. This includes observables such as vital signs, hemodynamics, intake/output, EKG, obstetric ultrasound, and cardiac echo, and includes discrete and narrative diagnostic observations and reports.

US Core DocumentReference Category |

The US Core DocumentReferences Category Value Set is a 'starter set' of categories supported for fetching and storing clinical notes.

US Core DocumentReference Type |

The US Core DocumentReference Type Value Set includes all LOINC values whose SCALE is "Doc" in the LOINC database and the HL7 v3 Code System NullFlavor concept 'unknown'

US Core Location Type Codes |

This value set represents the types of locations and organizational settings where healthcare services, encounters, or treatments occur, and is composed of several value sets to meet multiple industry needs. It includes HL7 Terminology (THO), SNOMED CT, National Healthcare Safety Network (NHSN), and CMS Place of Service Codes (POS) concepts.

US Core Narrative Status |

The US Core Narrative Status Value Set limits the text status for the resource narrative.

US Core Status for Smoking Status Observation |

Codes providing the status of an observation for smoking status. Constrained to final and entered-in-error.

US Core Practitioner Role Specialty Codes |

This value set represents the clinical specialty or functional role played by a clinician or provider. It is composed of two value sets, and include the National Uniform Claims Committee (NUCC) and SNOMED CT concepts.

US Core Screening Assessment Condition Category |

This value set consists of the single code "sdoh". It is the minimum value set of category codes used in the US Core Condition Problems and Health Concerns Profile that any conformant system SHALL support to help identify the type of USCDI Health Status/Assessment data class being reported.

US Core Screening Assessment Observation Category |

This value set is the minimum value set of category codes used in the US Core Observation Screening Assessment and Simple Observation Profiles that any conformant system SHALL support to help identify the type of USCDI Health Status/Assessment data class being reported.

US Core Screening Assessment Observation Maximum Category |

This value set is a value set of category codes used in the US Core Observation Screening Assessment that any conformant system SHOULD support to help identify the type of USCDI Health Status/Assessment data class being reported.

US Core Simple Observation Category |

This value set is a value set of category codes used in the US Core Simple Observation and Condition Problems and Health Concerns Profiles that any conformant system SHOULD support to help identify the type of USCDI Health Status/Assessment data class being reported.

US Core Specimen Condition |

This value set contains concepts the provide information regarding a specimen, including the container, that does not meet a laboratory’s criteria for acceptability.

US Core Condition Codes |

This describes the problem. Diagnosis/Problem List is broadly defined as a series of brief statements that catalog a patient's medical, nursing, dental, social, preventative and psychiatric events and issues that are relevant to that patient's healthcare (e.g., signs, symptoms, and defined conditions). ICD-10 is appropriate for Diagnosis information, and ICD-9 for historical information.

US Core Goal Codes |

Concepts from SNOMED CT and LOINC code systems that can be used to indicate the goal.

US Core Laboratory Test Codes |

Laboratory LOINC codes: From the introduction to August 2022 LOINC Users' guide; "The current scope of the existing laboratory portion of the LOINC database includes all observations reported by clinical laboratories, including the specialty areas: chemistry, including therapeutic drug monitoring and toxicology; hematology; serology; blood bank; microbiology; cytology; surgical pathology; and fertility.

US Core Problem or Health Concern |

Code set for category codes for US Core Condition Problems and Health Concerns Profile consisting of the concepts "problem" and "health-concern".

US Core Procedure Codes |

Concepts from CPT, SNOMED CT, HCPCS Level II Alphanumeric Codes, ICD-10-PCS, CDT and LOINC code systems that can be used to indicate the type of procedure performed.

US Core ServiceRequest Category Codes |

A set of SNOMED CT and LOINC concepts to classify a requested service

{% endraw %}

{% raw %}

Defining URL: | http://hl7.org/fhir/us/core/ValueSet/us-core-condition-code
Version: | 9.0.0
Name: | USCoreConditionCodes
Title: | US Core Condition Codes
Status: | Active as of 2022-09-29 (Standards Status: Trial Use)
Definition: |

This describes the problem. Diagnosis/Problem List is broadly defined as a series of brief statements that catalog a patient's medical, nursing, dental, social, preventative and psychiatric events and issues that are relevant to that patient's healthcare (e.g., signs, symptoms, and defined conditions). ICD-10 is appropriate for Diagnosis information, and ICD-9 for historical information.

Publisher: | HL7 International / Cross-Group Projects. HL7 International / Cross-Group Projects, , Email
Committee: | Cross-Group Projects
Copyright: |

This value set includes content from SNOMED CT, which is copyright © 2002+ International Health Terminology Standards Development Organisation (IHTSDO), and distributed by agreement between IHTSDO and HL7. Implementer use of SNOMED CT is not covered by this agreement.

ICD-9 and ICD-10 are copyrighted by the World Health Organization (WHO) which owns and publishes the classification. See https://www.who.int/classifications/icd/en. WHO has authorized the development of an adaptation of ICD-9 and ICD-10 to ICD-9-CM to ICD-10-CM for use in the United States for U.S. government purposes.

Maturity: | 3
OID: | 2.16.840.1.113883.4.642.40.2.48.16 (null (for OID based terminology systems))
Source Resource: | XML / JSON / Turtle

{% endraw %}

{% raw %}

Defining URL: | http://hl7.org/fhir/us/core/ValueSet/us-core-procedure-code
Version: | 9.0.0
Name: | USCoreProcedureCodes
Title: | US Core Procedure Codes
Status: | Active as of 2022-09-29 (Standards Status: Trial Use)
Definition: |

Concepts from CPT, SNOMED CT, HCPCS Level II Alphanumeric Codes, ICD-10-PCS, CDT and LOINC code systems that can be used to indicate the type of procedure performed.

Publisher: | HL7 International / Cross-Group Projects. HL7 International / Cross-Group Projects, , Email
Committee: | Cross-Group Projects
Copyright: |

Current Procedural Terminology (CPT) is copyright 2020 American Medical Association. All rights reserved
This value set includes content from SNOMED CT, which is copyright © 2002+ International Health Terminology Standards Development Organisation (IHTSDO), and distributed by agreement between IHTSDO and HL7. Implementer use of SNOMED CT is not covered by this agreement.
HCPCS Level II Alphanumeric Codes codes are maintained by the US Center for Medicare and Medicaid Services (CMS) available for public use.
The International Classification of Diseases, Tenth Revision, Procedure Coding System (ICD-10-PCS) was developed for the Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services (CMS) available for public use. CMS is the U.S. governmental agency responsible for overseeing all changes and modifications to the ICD-10-PCS.
The ADA is the exclusive copyright owner of CDT, the Code on Dental Procedures and Nomenclature (the Code), and the ADA Dental Claim Form. Except as permitted by law, all use, copying or distribution of CDT, or any portion thereof (including the Code on Dental Procedures and Nomenclature) in any product or services (including works prepared for clients by consultants and other professionals), whether in printed, electronic or other format, requires a valid commercial user license from the ADA. CDT ® is a registered trademark of the American Dental Association. All Rights Reserved.
This material contains content from LOINC (http://loinc.org). LOINC is copyright © 1995-2020, Regenstrief Institute, Inc. and the Logical Observation Identifiers Names and Codes (LOINC) Committee and is available at no cost under the license at http://loinc.org/license. LOINC® is a registered United States trademark of Regenstrief Institute, Inc

Maturity: | 3
OID: | 2.16.840.1.113883.4.642.40.2.48.20 (null (for OID based terminology systems))
Source Resource: | XML / JSON / Turtle

{% endraw %}